Nice job!
大家辛苦了
What should we do after this?
接下來要做什麼呢?
Hmm, I guess I'll go home.
這個嘛,我就直接回家吧
Oh, what about you, Mana?
真奈,妳呢?
I saw a cutie at the dressing room booths, so I think I'll go see her!
剛剛在待機室的隔間 發現一個可愛的女生,我想去看看她
You sure do like the cute ones.
妳真的很喜歡可愛的女生呢
Such an otaku.
真是個偶像宅
Which stage?
在哪個舞台?
Star Stage.
星之舞台
Ah, that hellhole.
啊,那個地獄啊
It's so hot there.
那邊超熱的呢
Hey, Boss, can we stay and watch the next stage too?
店長,要不要接著看下一個舞台?
Mem-cho's performing.
MEM啾要出場了喔
I've heard of the name. Who is she?
這名字我倒是聽過,誰來著?
She's a streamer. She's cute and funny.
是個網路主播,人又可愛又有趣
She was on this show called Love For Real recently.
最近才上過叫《現戀》的節目
Ah, the one that received backlash.
我知道,那個遭炎上的節目啊
That girl joined this group called B Komachi.
那女孩加入了一個叫B小町的團體喔
B Komachi?
B小町?
You've heard of it?
你有聽過嗎?
I guess kids nowadays don't know.
現在的孩子都不知道了吧
They inherited the name of an old group.
這是沿用了以前的一個團名
There was this legendary girl called Ai in it.
那個團體有個叫愛的傳奇偶像
She was just amazing, but she died midway through her career.
她真的很了不起 可是卻在演藝生涯的中途不幸逝世了
But even if they have the same group name...
也只有團名一樣而已吧
Well, let's just watch a little before we leave.
不過,我們稍微看一下再回去吧
B Komachi, you're on.
B小町,到妳們了
Okay!
-好耶!
The size of the crowd isn't bad.
觀眾人數不算少
I wasn't too worried since we have an influencer in our group.
畢竟我們團裡有個網紅嘛 這方面我沒有擔心過
But also many red penlights stand out more than I thought.
但紅色的螢光棒比我想的還要顯眼
My penlight color will be red!
螢光棒的應援色我就選紅色啦
The same color as Ai's!
跟愛一樣的顏色
Then I guess I'll be yellow.
那我就選黃色吧
And you, Senpai?
學姐呢?
Oh. Hmm...
咦?嗯...
If anything's okay, white.
什麼顏色都行的話,就白色
White, huh...
白色啊
Oh, is that not allowed?
嗯?不行嗎?
It is allowed, but some girls see it as special and unfair,
也不是不行啦,但因為白色很顯眼 要是有團員覺得不公平
so they tend to argue about it.
很容易會吵起來喔
Really...
這樣啊
Why not?
也好啊
Since you're not an idol otaku, it's very like you.
很適合學姐這種非偶像宅的風格喔
B Komachi!
- B小町!
I'm fine.
沒問題
Once I get up on stage, I'm not really nervous.
一旦站到舞台上,就不怎麼緊張了
The customers in the front are mostly waving yellow lights.
前排的觀眾 幾乎都揮舞著黃色的螢光棒
Our customers are mainly here for Mem-cho.
我們的觀眾 大多是衝著MEM啾而來的
Everyone's here so they can see her.
大家都是為了看她
I'm sure the customers would've been happier if she was the center.
如果讓她當C位的話 觀眾一定會更開心吧
What do you think as an OG B Komachi otaku?
作為元老級的B小町宅 有什麼感想呢?
They're completely different. This isn't B Komachi.
完全沾不上邊,這根本就不是B小町
That group was upheld by a star called Ai.
那個團體全靠 名為愛的這顆明星才能成立
Just gathering three amateurs...
像這樣隨便拉三個湊數的...
Boss?!
店長?
Oh, this girl is so bright.
啊,這孩子好耀眼啊
Thank you so much!
謝謝大家!
She loves idols and she's always upbeat.
真心誠意地喜愛著偶像 總是享受著這一切
It's like she was born to become an idol.
簡直像是為了成為偶像而出生的一樣
Even at this very second, she's grabbing someone's heart
即便在這個瞬間 她也不斷在虜獲觀眾們的心
and she's gaining more fans.
增加自己的粉絲
These are the girls who rise to the top.
這樣的孩子肯定能爬得更高吧
Next up is that megahit song you've all been waiting for!
接下來是大家 期待已久的那首熱門歌曲
"Sign is B!"
《暗號是B》
I envy them.
好羨慕啊
For being watched over and desired by everyone.
能像那樣被大家關注著、追逐著
There's no one who'll look at me.
我卻沒有半個注視著我的人
My mom and my manager neglected me.
媽媽和經紀人都對我置之不理
Even our fans only see the old child star in me.
粉絲的眼裡 也只看得到過去的我的影子
"Somebody, please look at me."
“拜託了,誰來看看我啊”
That's all I've been screaming for the past dozen years.
明明這十幾年來,我一直如此吶喊著
"Please say that you need me."
“告訴我你需要我啊”
If you just tell me that, I'll work as hard as I possibly can.
只要對我這麼說 我一定會拼了命地努力的
"Say that you can use me."
“告訴我我是能派上用場的啊”
Then I'll work like a dog for you.
即使要我做牛做馬,我也心甘情願
"Tell me that I did a good job."
“誇讚我做得很好啊”
Then I'll work even harder.
那我一定會付出更多更多努力的
Somebody...
拜託了
Tell me that I belong here!
找個人來告訴我 這裡就是我的安身之處啊
He's so stupid!
有夠傻的!
What's he doing while keeping a straight face?!
一臉嚴肅地在搞什麼啊?
He even bothered to wave all three of our color lights.
甚至還拿齊了我們三個人的螢光棒
Does this mean he's a fan of every member? You cheater!
這是打算全推嗎?你這個花心大蘿蔔
I've made up my mind.
我決定了
While I'm an idol, I swear I'll turn all of your lights white.
在我的偶像生涯裡 一定要將你的螢光棒統統染成白色
I'll make you love me.
絕對要讓你最喜歡我一個
I'll become your favorite!
我要成為你推的孩子!
Boss, isn't that girl nice too?
店長,那孩子好像也挺不錯的吧?
Her expression has been getting better since the first song.
從第一首歌開始 表情就越來越進入狀態
I can honestly be her fan.
說實話可以推喔
All three of them have the looks of an ace idol in other groups.
以這三個人的外貌來說 就算單獨放在其他團體也能成為王牌
Especially that girl in the center would be loved by otaku and she can sing.
尤其是中間的那個女生 一看就是宅男的喜好,唱功也不錯
They might get popular.
說不定會紅喔
I'm so tired!
累死人了
Oh, Bro, you were here?
哦,哥哥,你來啦?
Well, yeah.
是啊
By the way, what was that back there? I couldn't stop myself from laughing!
話說剛才那是在幹嘛啊? 害人家笑場了啦
How was our performance?
你覺得我們的表演如何?
Well, I guess you guys did good for your first time.
這個嘛 以初次登台來說,算是還不錯吧
What? Compliment us some more!
什麼啊?多說點誇讚的話啊
I can't do that.
那可不行
Since you guys are going to do bigger and better concerts from here.
因為妳們往後 會展現出更多更棒的現場表演
Considering that, it's a waste to give you guys a high score now.
考慮到這點 現在就給出高分的話就太浪費了
Is that so.
這樣啊
Those two finally decided to talk to each other.
那兩個人 看來總算願意跟對方說話了啊
They don't seem like they get along.
感覺他們關係不太好呢
It's not what you think.
不是妳想的那樣喔
Hey Aqua, are you doing well with Akane from Love For Real?
欸,阿奎亞 你跟《現戀》的小茜相處得還好嗎?
No, I haven't seen her since the party.
沒有,節目結束之後就沒見過面了
Really?
是嗎?
Well, she's just a work colleague after all.
我跟她只有工作上的關係
But we're talking about going to take photos together to post on Instagram.
不過我們有說過要一起去拍照 然後上傳到IG上
Work...
工作...
That's right!
也對啦
That Akane Kurokawa would never get serious over someone like you!
那個黑川茜 怎麼可能真的對你這種人動心嘛?
It's all an act for the TV show! This is pretty common, you know.
那只不過是節目效果啊 是常有的事呢
Poor you!
真是可憐呢
You can't take these things seriously!
這種事不能當真啦
Oh gosh, are you seriously upset?
不會吧?你真的受傷了嗎?
Arima, you're so smiley all of a sudden...
有馬突然間就開朗起來了...
Is that what this is?!
是這樣嗎?
Arima has a thing for Aqua!
有馬對阿奎...
Akane!
小茜!
Who am I supposed to root for?!
那我該支持哪邊才好啊?
Akane, your next job's decided.
小茜,妳的下一份工作定下來了
Oh, is this true?
咦?這是真的嗎?
Aqua, we'll be able to work together again.
阿奎亞,又能跟你一起工作了
You were the one behind Pieyon's mask during our lessons, right?
我們特訓的時候 你一直在假扮啾啾仔,對吧?
Why did you do something like that?
為什麼要幹那種事?
Because you wouldn't talk to me.
因為妳都不肯跟我說話啊
That's it?
就這樣?
That's the only reason?
就只因為這個理由?
That's why you were running and dancing with that hot mask on?
就因為這個,你就戴著 那個熱死人的頭套又跑步又跳舞啊?
I did it once too, but wasn't it tough as hell?
我也試過一次,真的很要命吧?
And you were talking in that creepy voice?
而且你還得發出那把噁心的聲音?
But hey, you're good at impressions!
不過,你模仿得還真像呢
You got yourself a surprising skill. Wow!
沒想到你居然有這種特技,好厲害喔
Like I said, if you wouldn't talk to me, you would never listen to my directions.
我是說,既然有馬妳不肯跟我說話 肯定也不會接受我的指導吧
It was just to make my sister's first concert a success--
我只是想確保妹妹的初次登台成功...
Sure, sure. This is one of your sister complex moves again.
知道了...又是你的妹控舉動,是吧?
You have such a convenient excuse.
真是個方便的藉口呢
I'll leave it as that for you!
就讓你用這個理由搪塞過去吧
What's with you? I'm leaving.
這傢伙是怎麼回事?我回去了
You running? You running?
要逃跑了嗎?
What are you talking about? I'm not running from anything.
嗯?完全搞不懂妳說什麼 沒什麼值得我逃跑的啊
Just because I found out you did something weird to talk to me,
你這不是被我發現 你為了跟我說上話而做出奇怪的行為
you're gonna run because you're embarrassed?
覺得太尷尬了,所以要逃跑嗎?
Fine, you seem to have the wrong idea, so let's talk this out.
我懂了,看來妳會錯意了 我們就來好好說清楚吧
Sit down.
坐下
Bring it on!
這正合我意呢
I'm glad it seems like those two made up!
看來那兩個人和好了,真是太棒了
But it also seems like things are just about to get worse.
我倒覺得看起來關係正要開始惡化呢
It's okay, Bro's not the type who likes to get involved with others.
沒事的啦 哥哥不是那種喜歡跟人往來的類型
If you don't provoke him like that, your relationship with him wouldn't last.
如果不那樣刺激他的話 跟他的關係沒辦法長久的
He wasn't like that before though.
明明以前也不是這樣的說
Really?
是嗎?
Well, a lot happened and he developed a twisted personality.
總之就是發生了很多事 搞得他的性格都扭曲了
Oh.
這樣啊
When he's with Senpai, he seems a bit like his old self though.
反而跟學姐一起的時候 看起來才有點像以前的哥哥
Akane... you gotta work a little harder.
小茜,妳得稍微加把勁了喔
Well! I've got us our first big title in a long time!
太好了,時隔那麼久 總算又拿下熱門作品的版權啦
Over a total of 50 million copies sold! Its anime film was a megahit too!
累計銷售量超過五千萬本 動畫電影也超級賣座
The theatrical adaptation project of the almighty popular manga, Tokyo Blade!
無人不知的人氣漫畫 《東京劍士》的舞台化企劃
Oh, I know this!
這個啊,我知道喔
My daughter's hooked on this from the anime.
我家女兒看了動漫之後也迷上了呢
Theatrical means it's 2.5D, huh?
舞台化的意思 是2.5次元舞台劇吧?
That's right!
沒錯...
I've got a huge budget for it, so we're gonna make it flashy this time!
預算也談到了很大一筆 這次讓我們大幹一場吧
The stage is an interesting place too!
這次的舞台也很有趣喔
The seats rotate 360 degrees and the stage uses computer graphics
座位360度環繞 能用電腦合成影像
to recreate the original story's atmosphere!
重現原作裡的氛圍
I've secured a good crew too!
可靠的幕後工作人員也已經找好了
And for the adaptation, I've added on Theater Lalalai's cooperation.
至於舞台化的合作對象 我也取得了拉拉萊劇團的協助
Oh, that's exciting.
哦,這下就熱鬧了
I'm surprised you were able to talk Mr. Kindaichi into doing it.
你居然能說服那個金田一先生參與啊
Money talks. Since any theater has it tough financially.
多虧有龐大的預算啦 畢竟做舞台表演的大多都經費不足啊
All that's left is the casting.
最後就剩出演陣容了
We can probably get Akane Kurokawa from Lalalai.
拉拉萊劇團那裡應該會讓黑川茜參與
But pretty boys and cute girls will be essential for our target audience.
不過,從目標受眾的角度來看 帥哥美女是必不可少的
Lalalai doesn't have many young actors,
拉拉萊沒那麼多年輕演員
so we'll need to bring some in from the outside.
所以還是得找外面的演員參與
Kaburagi, you've got strong connections there, don't you?
這方面果然得靠 人脈資源豐富的小鏑木才行呢
You know any good ones?
有沒有不錯的人選啊?
Well, I may know a few.
也不是沒有啦
Some up-and-coming young ones.
而且都是大有前途的年輕人
I can introduce you, but you'll owe me one.
我可以給你介紹 但這就算欠我一個人情了喔
No, no!
這怎麼行?
I'm giving the kids you're looking after a chance to grow,
我這是給小鏑木關照的孩子們 一個成長的機會啊
so actually, you'll owe me one!
應該算是我賣你一個人情才對吧
Then it's a deal.
那就成交了
PROJECT PROPOSAL
(《東京劍士》公演企劃書)
Is this good?
這樣應該可以吧?
I don't know, but I guess it's good.
我不太會,應該不錯吧
Now, we've made our boyfriend-girlfriend alibi for our fans.
總之呢,這樣就算是 上傳了給粉絲們看的交往證明
So we'll be good for a while.
暫時應該沒問題了
About that one job... has the news reached you?
上次說的那件事 有人聯絡你們了嗎?
Is it about Tokyo Blade?
妳說《東京劍士》嗎?
Yeah.
是啊
The theatrical troupe that I belong to called Lalalai will be leading it,
我所屬的拉拉萊劇團 是出演團隊的中心
so I've received an offer too.
所以我也得到了相關的工作
Theater Lalalai...
拉拉萊劇團
I thought it might help her somehow,
我想說可能對她有幫助
so I introduced her to this one theater's workshop.
就給她介紹了某個劇團的培訓班
A workshop?
培訓班?
It's called Theater Lalalai.
拉拉萊劇團
The theater group that Akane belongs to.
也就是小茜所屬的劇團
It wasn't that famous at the time though.
不過那時候他們的名氣沒那麼大
That's probably the place...
那裡應該就是...
where Ai fell in love.
愛墜入愛河的地方吧
Ever since Ai joined that workshop, she started to care about her appearance.
自從參加那個培訓班之後 她開始在意自己的打扮
And she would ask me where the good restaurants were.
還問我有沒有什麼推薦的好餐廳
Of course I couldn't tell who her dates were,
雖然我也不知道對方是誰
but I remember she suddenly looked all grown-up.
但我記得 她彷彿一夕之間變得很有女人味
If you're curious, I'll introduce you to Lalalai's superintendent.
有興趣的話 我可以給你介紹拉拉萊劇團的負責人
You'll surely get closer to the answer you're looking for there.
在那裡的話 你一定會更接近你想知道的答案吧
I'm doing it.
我當然會接了
Right?
我想也是
I got an offer to play Princess Saya, and you'll be Touki, right?
我接到的角色是鞘姬 你的角色是刀鬼,對吧?
The two roles are a couple.
這兩個角色是情侶
I bet whoever chose the cast did this on purpose.
我想負責選角的人一定是故意的吧
I hear there's a high demand for BL in 2.5D, but is this okay?
我以為2.5次元舞台劇對BL的 需求比較多,這樣的也有嗎?
It's because the original story has mainly male and female couplings.
因為原作裡比較多異性的情侶組合啊
Of course, many girls tend to have that kind of view though.
當然了,也有很多女生 會從那個角度去欣賞
Touki's a side character,
雖說刀鬼是配角
but he's pretty popular among men too due to the rom-com elements.
但因為有浪漫喜劇的元素 所以也很受男性的歡迎
Every week, everybody's discussing if he'll get with the heroine or his partner.
每週都有人討論 他會跟女主角還是跟搭檔在一起喔
Touki's partner, Tsurugi...
刀鬼的搭檔是劍儀吧
That role should also be filled soon.
那個角色的演員也差不多快定下來了
I wonder who it'll be.
不知道會是誰呢
Me.
是我
Arima.
有馬
Don't do live posts.
以後不要再這樣實時上傳照片
These types of posts can draw troublesome fans into stalking you.
這樣的貼文可能會 引來惡意的粉絲跟蹤你們
For any photos taken outside, it's a basic rule to schedule posts.
在外面拍的照片 都要用預約發文功能,這是基本常識
Did you wanna cause trouble again by making a weird fuss?
難道又想引起什麼糾紛 給身邊的人添麻煩嗎?
You need to learn, Akane Kurokawa.
妳還真是學不乖呢,黑川茜
Kana, you're playing Tsurugi?
劍儀這個角色由佳奈來飾演啊?
How long has it been since we were cast together?
我們上次同台演出是多少年前啦?
I surely thought you quit acting.
我還以為妳不再當演員了呢
Since you're an idol now, right?
畢竟妳現在是偶像了嘛
Akane?
小茜?
What's the point of locking yourself up in a stage that doesn't make any money?
總不能像妳一樣 老是待在賺不了多少錢的小舞台上啊
Oh! That's right, you were on some reality dating show lately.
啊,說起來 妳最近出演戀愛實境秀了吧?
I heard you finally got popular from selling off your private life.
聽說靠著出賣自己的私生活 換取了一點點人氣啊
Good for you!
真是太好了呢
Arima?
有馬?
Well... I came to warn you guys because I was just nearby.
好啦,我剛好在附近 才會過來提醒你們一下
Continue your business date after you change location.
換個地方之後 再繼續你們的業務約會吧
Bye.
我走啦
You know Arima?
原來妳認識有馬啊?
We're the same age and we've been in the same industry since we were kids,
我們年齡相同 又都是從童星時期開始就待在這圈子
so of course.
當然認識了
Well, try to get along.
那個,試著好好相處吧
That's impossible.
我做不到
She's always taken all of the jobs that I wanted to do.
從以前開始 我想演的角色總是被她搶走
Try to imagine...
你想像一下啊
how it feels to be an actress born the same year as that genius child star.
跟那個天才童星同歲的演員 會有什麼感受
But I won't lose now.
但是,現在的我不會輸給她了
While Kana was releasing that ridiculous "Green Pepper Exercise,"
在佳奈發行那首 可笑的《大青椒體操》的時候
I was always doing my acting lessons.
我可是一直不斷地練習演技
This is my chance to finally get my revenge.
讓我一雪前恥的機會終於來了
I won't lose this time.
我不會輸的
Why are all actors...
演員的圈子裡...
I won't lose to her.
絕對不能輸...
...so competitive?
不服輸的人還真多啊
The child actress formerly known as a genius
過去曾被稱為天才的童星
and the actress currently known as a genius.
以及目前正被稱為天才的演員
Kaburagi's clever but cruel to put these two against each other.
讓這兩人對上的小鏑木 還真是老奸巨猾啊
Now, I'm personally looking forward to Tokyo Blade's stage!
《東京劍士》的舞台劇 我個人也開始期待了啊
I think that you might become an idol yourself one day, Ruby.
我一直在想 露比妳將來說不定也會成為偶像呢
And maybe Aqua might be an actor?
阿奎亞你也許會當演員?
I wonder what kind of adults you two will become.
好想知道 你們將來會變成什麼樣的大人
The culprit who put Ai to such a fate is in the entertainment industry.
害死愛的幕後黑手就在演藝圈之中
I'll find them no matter what it takes.
無論用上什麼手段 我都一定要把他找出來
If it's for that, I'll...
為了這個目的,我...
Subtitle translation by: Kanami Kitabayashi
字幕翻譯:蔡曉琳